<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>one-piece on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/one-piece/</link>
    <description>Recent content in one-piece on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/one-piece/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>March and April 2023 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2023/04/17/march-april-2023-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2023/04/17/march-april-2023-update/</guid>
      <description>March started slow with sickness and bad weather, then ended with even more snow. Throughout the month I continued making progress on digitizing the SF3 design into 3D for future CAD/CAM options. For now I will be doing a lot of the work on this next SF3 by hand because I don&#39;t want to waste any of this good weather on the computer. Speaking of the new SF3, there is some new progress here and at the project page below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chambered Claro Walnut SF3 Carve Top Guitar</title>
      <link>/in-progress/chambered-claro-walnut-sf3-carve-top-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/in-progress/chambered-claro-walnut-sf3-carve-top-guitar/</guid>
      <description>The first step toward a new generation of SF3 Guitars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SF3co Eco Guitar Prototype</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3co-eco-guitar-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3co-eco-guitar-prototype/</guid>
      <description>I started this prototype and the potential line of instruments it represented after taking a break from lutherie. It marked a shift in how I think about guitars and how I go about working on a project. Even though it was ultimately not a success, I did learn a lot about doing things I actually care about. The response to this instrument from potential customers was very strong and the fact that I didn&#39;t build a ton of them for excited customers really has more to do with my own personal situation starting a family and nothing to do with players&#39; appetite for &#39;alternative&#39; instruments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claro Walnut SF3 Singlecut Bass Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This was the rare instrument I actuatlly built on spec and the whole thing just went quick and easy.
I lucked into this beautiful and THICK Claro Walnut body blank that just perfectly fit with this 
singlecut SF3 bodystyle. I already had all the hardware and electronics around so this project came together
in a matter of days. It ended up going to local person with some interesting stories and a great instrument</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenge &amp; Mahogany SF3 Chambered Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/wenge-mahogany-sf3-chambered-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/wenge-mahogany-sf3-chambered-guitar/</guid>
      <description>There was a time when it was very hard to find to find wenge locally so I generally grabbed
it whenever it did show up. With that spirit one day I visited my most local, small town lumber
store and found some HUGE wenge slabs with plenty of space for multiple one-piece tops. I bought
all the clean boards and have been using them ever since. For me this guitar really was all</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swamp Ash SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/swamp-ash-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/swamp-ash-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This is a project that evolved a lot from start to finish, but one goal all along was to make a very light
guitar. This one-piece swamp ash body was light to start, but I had the face sliced off so we could
do some chambering and make it even lighter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claro Walnut SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s an amazing thing when you get your first real customer. Working at the First Act Studio for Artists I had already worked on a good amount
of instruments for big names, and I was lucky enough to have some awesome musicians as friends that I had built for, but this was my first
real customer. We exchanged a few emails about the specs then one day a check showed up and I started building.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
