<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>december-2022-update on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/december-2022-update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in december-2022-update on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/december-2022-update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>December 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/12/30/december-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/12/30/december-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>The last few months of the year are always busy around here. Holidays, birthdays, anniversaries, school events, and end-of-year work always means there is no free time. It&#39;s been a great and full year for my family so I have no complaints, but I have not been able to touch anything guitar related in some time. I&#39;m coming into the New Year with even more focus than last year, so I&#39;m excited for the coming months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Imbuia &amp; Wicker Thiele Compact Ported Cab</title>
      <link>/journal/2021/01/04/mesa-boogie-thiele-cabinet-imbuia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2021/01/04/mesa-boogie-thiele-cabinet-imbuia/</guid>
      <description>This is the Holy Grail of Mesa cabs, a vintage hardwood &amp; wicker Thiele with Electro-Voice EVM-12L from 1987. When you consider this thing is over 30 years old it is in pretty nice shape. It was made using amazing 13&#34; wide imbuia boards. Condition is pretty nice overall. There are dents and dings throughout, but overall it presents pretty well. Weight is 48lbs. I&#39;ve purchased this cab twice and both times it was poorly packaged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Hardwood &amp; Wicker Dual Rectifier Blue Angel 2x10&#34; Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/04/04/mesa-boogie-hardwood-dual-rectifier-blue-angel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/04/04/mesa-boogie-hardwood-dual-rectifier-blue-angel/</guid>
      <description>This Blue Angel combo is a really cool and very un-Mesa like amp. I don&#39;t think they ever made and another 2x10&#34; as far as I remember and to find one in hardwood was an amazing surprise. There are no markings inside, but if I had to guess I would say it is Imbuia. The power section of this amp mixing tube types with switchable combinations is also very strange and worth looking into if you&#39;re interested in something different for Mesa Boogie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Thiele Ported Compact Cab in Imbuia Hardwood &amp; Wicker</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/01/09/mesa-boogie-thiele-cabinet-imbuia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/01/09/mesa-boogie-thiele-cabinet-imbuia/</guid>
      <description>This is the Holy Grail of Mesa cabs, a vintage hardwood &amp; wicker Thiele with EVM-12L from the Mark III era. When you consider this thing is around 30 years old it is in pretty nice shape. It was made using amazing 13&#34; wide imbuia boards. Condition is pretty nice overall. There are dents and dings throughout, and also some substantial scratches on top from amp feet. The speaker and it has a 1989 date code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Padauk &amp; Wicker Half-Back Speaker Cabinet</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/12/24/mesa-boogie-padauk-half-back-cabinet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/12/24/mesa-boogie-padauk-half-back-cabinet/</guid>
      <description>This is a beautiful Mesa speaker cabinet, a vintage hardwood &amp; wicker half-back with original EVM-12L from the early 80s. When you consider this thing is around 35 years old it is in almost perfect shape. It was made using amazing 11&#34; wide boards. Based on the grain and era I think this may be padauk. There are no factory markings inside the cab but based on the logo plate and jack mount it looks to be from the Mark II/IIB/IIC/IIC+ era.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Hardwood &amp; Wicker Mark IIC Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/01/17/mesa-boogie-hardwood-wicker-mark-iic-combo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/01/17/mesa-boogie-hardwood-wicker-mark-iic-combo/</guid>
      <description>This is a very clean Mark IIC in its original hardwood &amp; wicker cabinet. It&#39;s a 60 watt model with reverb. The speaker is a Mesa/Celestion Black Shadow MC-90. I am not sure the wood species, but it does seem to fit in with other hardwood Mark series amps of this era. My guess would be padauk. When I purchased this amp I was told it had a recent service/cleaning including new caps and power cord.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
