<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>update on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in update on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>August 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/08/31/july-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/08/31/july-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>All things considered August was a good month on the guitar front. I started the month working on my first ever pedalboard. I have been collecting parts and planning for years but it&#39;s finally time to put it all together. Almost immediately I ran into shipping delays on some essential parts so the project is currently on hold, but I hope to finish the first version in September if there are no more delays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/07/06/july-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/07/06/july-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>For anyone paying attention, you probably noticed that June came and went without an update. The reason is pretty simple, I didn&#39;t really do anything guitar related in June. School ended and my kids started their summer break. I got on a plane for the first time in fifteen years and we all took a trip to Nashville and Atlanta. We had a lot of fun there, Nashville is an interesting place and there&#39;s lots of guitar content all over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/05/28/may-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/05/28/may-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>Before I launched this new site in April my hope was I would be able to to make a new journal entry each week, but during the process of getting the site finished and released I realized once per month was much more likely. April was a busy month with my wife Brianna away most of the time working a new mural. May turned out to be just as busy with several small building projects, an overnight class field trip, and lots of other family, work, and house projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Website for 2022</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/04/10/website-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/04/10/website-updates/</guid>
      <description>Hello! Thanks for reading this. Building a new website has been a long time coming. I guess you could think of it as a more serious step in my eventual return to lutherie. I&#39;ve been away from guitar building in any productive capacity since around 2008. I have worked on some projects since then, but not a lot since 2011. Around 2018 I was in therapy working through a particularly tough time in my life, and going through that process really reawakened the desire to build instruments again.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
