<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pickups on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/pickups/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pickups on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/pickups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>January 2023 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2023/01/31/january-2023-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2023/01/31/january-2023-update/</guid>
      <description>January was a great month full of learning, and as a result some new progress was made on the next SF3! I&#39;ve wanted to learn 3D CAD/CAM for many years but have always been intimidated by the complexity. It was a great moment when I found out that I could do simple 2.5D CAD/CAM using Illustrator SVGs when I first got the CNC. Being able to work with software and concepts that I was already familiar with was great because it allowed me focused on the initial challenge of learning how to run a CNC and use basic CAD/CAM software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Pickup for Christian Allen Luthiery</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/05/24/custom-pickup-christian-allen-luthiery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/05/24/custom-pickup-christian-allen-luthiery/</guid>
      <description>Christian is a great local luthier and fellow Roberto-Venn graduate. He&#39;s been building some really interesting instruments recently and this is the third custom pickup I&#39;ve made for him. For this project he needed a magnetic humbucking pickup to cover only three closely spaced strings. This post gives you an idea of how these projects can go. I recieve some basic dimensions from Christian, then digitize those in Adobe Illustrator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Handmade Question</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/04/02/the-handmade-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/04/02/the-handmade-question/</guid>
      <description>The previous entry in this four part series found me reconnecting with the parts of lutherie that inspired me from the start and deciding to move forward with guitar building in ways I never considered. This entry is an extension of that reconsideration of all things held holy in guitar building. 
If you went back and looked at my first website from 2004, you&#39;d see I put a lot of emphasis on my instruments being handmade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coilton the Accuwinder CW-11B Coil Winding Machine</title>
      <link>/journal/2018/11/18/accuwinder-pickup-winder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2018/11/18/accuwinder-pickup-winder/</guid>
      <description>This was a serendipitous find. Years ago my therapist suggested I spend more idle time in the evening without a digital device in front of me. It took a while before I gave it a fair shot, but upon trying it out my mind started filling up with new ideas almost immediately. Very quickly it became obvious I needed a pickup winder to start working through some of these ideas. I had looked at buying winders before but they always felt fairly expensive for the limited functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
