<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>padauk on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/padauk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in padauk on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/padauk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1976 Mesa Boogie Mark I Combo - Factory Upgraded Simul-class DRG</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/04/14/padauk-mesa-boogie-mark-i-1976-drg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/04/14/padauk-mesa-boogie-mark-i-1976-drg/</guid>
      <description>This is a pretty special Mesa Boogie Mark I. It is an original Mark I, serial A802, and was made in late 1976. Just two amps before Keith Richard&#39;s legendary A804! This was originally a 100/60w amp, then factory upgraded to Simul-class in the mid eighties (transformer code is 1985). This upgrade work was confirmed to be factory performed when the amp was sent back to Mesa for a full service and cap job in April 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark IIB Coliseum Padauk Hardwood &amp; Wicker Big Brother</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/04/14/padauk-mesa-boogie-iib-coliseum-big-brother/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/04/14/padauk-mesa-boogie-iib-coliseum-big-brother/</guid>
      <description>This is a Mesa Boogie Mark IIB Coliseum, also known as the &#34;Series 300&#34;. It&#39;s a KG which mean switchable Coliseum 180-watt power section (K) and Graphic EQ (G) options are present. The speaker is an Electro-Voice EVM-15L. The included power tubes are very hard to find STR-415s as would have been included back in the 80s. Serial is K238. This amp was originally housed in a black bronco headshell, but was recently moved into this original Mesa Padauk hardwood &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Padauk &amp; Wicker Half-Back Speaker Cabinet</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/12/24/mesa-boogie-padauk-half-back-cabinet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/12/24/mesa-boogie-padauk-half-back-cabinet/</guid>
      <description>This is a beautiful Mesa speaker cabinet, a vintage hardwood &amp; wicker half-back with original EVM-12L from the early 80s. When you consider this thing is around 35 years old it is in almost perfect shape. It was made using amazing 11&#34; wide boards. Based on the grain and era I think this may be padauk. There are no factory markings inside the cab but based on the logo plate and jack mount it looks to be from the Mark II/IIB/IIC/IIC+ era.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark III/IIC&#43; Red Stripe Head, Simul-Class, GEQ</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/05/20/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-c-plus-head-drg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/05/20/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-c-plus-head-drg/</guid>
      <description>This is a 1987 Mesa Boogie Mark III Head. It&#39;s the Red Stripe version. It&#39;s fully loaded with Graphic EQ, Reverb, and Simul-class. It&#39;s also fully loaded in that it has the IIC+/III+ Upgrade, Reverb Fix, R2 Volume Mod, and a Triode/Pentode switch which you don&#39;t often see on these. That is just about every feature you can expect to find on a Mark III. On top of that, it comes in a beautiful Hardwood and Wicker headshell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1981 Imbuia Hardwood &amp; Wicker Mesa Boogie Mark IIB Combo Amp</title>
      <link>/journal/2016/08/26/padauk-mesa-boogie-mark-iib/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2016/08/26/padauk-mesa-boogie-mark-iib/</guid>
      <description>This is a beautiful 1981 Mesa Boogie Mark IIB combo. As far as I know/understand this amp is in completetly original.
It is in very nice condition, especially when you consider it is 35
years old. I contacted Mesa Boogie support and they think this cabinet is made from imbuya. That seems to be par for the
course for this era, but this certainly has more contrast in the grain than a lot of others I have seen listed as</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Padauk Hardwood &amp; Wicker Thiele Ported Cab Set</title>
      <link>/journal/2016/08/26/padauk-mesa-boogie-thiele/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2016/08/26/padauk-mesa-boogie-thiele/</guid>
      <description>This is the Holy Grail of Mesa cabs, a vintage hardwood &amp;amp; wicker Thiele with original EVM-12L from 1986. When you
consider this thing is around 30 years old it is in great shape. It was made using amazing 13&#34; wide padauk boards. The
condition is pretty good, but all the patina is also perfect to match a Mark head or combo from the era. I have
been looking for one of these for quite a while and was lucky enough to find an original matching pair.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
