<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bass on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/bass/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bass on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/bass/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1999 Taylor/Klein Imbuia AB-2 Acoustic Bass Guitar</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/09/22/1999-taylor-klein-ab-2-imbuia-acoustic-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/09/22/1999-taylor-klein-ab-2-imbuia-acoustic-bass/</guid>
      <description>I picked this up recently after about 20 years of wanting one. It&#39;s absolutely the nicest acoustic bass guitar I have played... but after owning it for a few weeks I think it is actually a little too nice for me. Oddly enough after so long waiting I lucked into a good deal on an another one of these (AB-1) that needs some work. I am going to let this one go and keep the one that needs some work as I am more of a tweaker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1990 Boire Warwick Dolphin Pro I Bass</title>
      <link>/journal/2018/05/09/boire-warwick-dolphin-pro-1-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2018/05/09/boire-warwick-dolphin-pro-1-bass/</guid>
      <description>This is a no-compromise early Warwick Dolphin Pro I with all the best features. Being a 1990 it&#39;s still in the Warwick &#34;handmade&#34; era. It has the coveted Boire Rosewood body instead of the later Ovangkol. Bartolini J+MM Pickups and 2-Band Pre-amp instead of later MEC. Satin Chrome (also called titanium or platinum) hardware including Schaller strap locks. 7-piece Wenge/Zebrano neck WITHOUT the volute like the later Dolphins. No modifications, missing pieces, or weird custom features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claro Walnut SF3 Singlecut Bass Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This was the rare instrument I actuatlly built on spec and the whole thing just went quick and easy.
I lucked into this beautiful and THICK Claro Walnut body blank that just perfectly fit with this 
singlecut SF3 bodystyle. I already had all the hardware and electronics around so this project came together
in a matter of days. It ended up going to local person with some interesting stories and a great instrument</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gum Eucalyptus &amp; Walnut SF3 Singlecut Bass</title>
      <link>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass/</guid>
      <description>This bass was pretty important in the evolution of my designs as it was the first neck to utilize the
overlapping headcap with individual string guides. From here I moved onto a differnt design using solid
metal rivets instead of delrin rods, but this was still an important step. Some really nice local woods
again here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gum Eucaluptus SF3 Singlecut Bass</title>
      <link>/instruments/red-gum-eucaluptus-sf3-singlecut-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/red-gum-eucaluptus-sf3-singlecut-bass/</guid>
      <description>This is the first instrument I built when I moved home to California. I setup most of my tools
while I was building this one so there are some rough edges, but it turned out pretty nice and
has been used plenty live and in the studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott&#39;s Old Guitars</title>
      <link>/instruments/scotts-old-guitars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/scotts-old-guitars/</guid>
      <description>Here are some guitars I made while attending The Roberto Venn School of Luthiery and my apprenticeship at the First Act Studio for Artists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
