<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal on Scott French</title>
    <link>/journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journal on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>July 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/07/06/july-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/07/06/july-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>For anyone paying attention, you probably noticed that June came and went without an update. The reason is pretty simple, I didn&#39;t really do anything guitar related in June. School ended and my kids started their summer break. I got on a plane for the first time in fifteen years and we all took a trip to Nashville and Atlanta. We had a lot of fun there, Nashville is an interesting place and there&#39;s lots of guitar content all over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/05/28/may-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/05/28/may-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>Before I launched this new site in April my hope was I would be able to to make a new journal entry each week, but during the process of getting the site finished and released I realized once per month was much more likely. April was a busy month with my wife Brianna away most of the time working a new mural. May turned out to be just as busy with several small building projects, an overnight class field trip, and lots of other family, work, and house projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Pickup for Christian Allen Luthiery</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/05/24/custom-pickup-christian-allen-luthiery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/05/24/custom-pickup-christian-allen-luthiery/</guid>
      <description>Christian is a great local luthier and fellow Roberto-Venn graduate. He&#39;s been building some really interesting instruments recently and this is the third custom pickup I&#39;ve made for him. For this project he needed a magnetic humbucking pickup to cover only three closely spaced strings. This post gives you an idea of how these projects can go. I recieve some basic dimensions from Christian, then digitize those in Adobe Illustrator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Website for 2022</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/04/10/website-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/04/10/website-updates/</guid>
      <description>Hello! Thanks for reading this. Building a new website has been a long time coming. I guess you could think of it as a more serious step in my eventual return to lutherie. I&#39;ve been away from guitar building in any productive capacity since around 2008. I have worked on some projects since then, but not a lot since 2011. Around 2018 I was in therapy working through a particularly tough time in my life, and going through that process really reawakened the desire to build instruments again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto of an Electric Guitar Builder</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/04/09/manifesto-of-an-electric-guitar-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/04/09/manifesto-of-an-electric-guitar-builder/</guid>
      <description>The previous entry in this four part series found me questioning some long held beliefs around the value of handmade instruments and making the decision to use all the modern tools available to me. This final entry outlines some of the other important choices that help shape my instruments. 
There&#39;s a famous document in the software world that was authored and co-signed by many of the most influential developers in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Handmade Question</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/04/02/the-handmade-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/04/02/the-handmade-question/</guid>
      <description>The previous entry in this four part series found me reconnecting with the parts of lutherie that inspired me from the start and deciding to move forward with guitar building in ways I never considered. This entry is an extension of that reconsideration of all things held holy in guitar building. 
If you went back and looked at my first website from 2004, you&#39;d see I put a lot of emphasis on my instruments being handmade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconnecting With Inspiration</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/03/26/reconnecting-with-inspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/03/26/reconnecting-with-inspiration/</guid>
      <description>The previous entry in this four part series found me questioning my place in the guitar world and eventually leaving to pursue other endeavors. We pick up almost ten years later when my therapist encouraged me to revisit lutherie looking for some long lost seeds of joy. 
I never really stopped thinking about guitars during the time I was away, but with work and family all I really had time for in the guitar world was thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Age Of Lutherie</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/03/19/the-golden-age-of-lutherie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/03/19/the-golden-age-of-lutherie/</guid>
      <description>We&#39;re living through what is often called The Golden Age of Lutherie. Whereas in the past luthiers and large companies tended to guard their secrets, we&#39;ve seen an explosion of communication and information sharing that&#39;s raised the standard for modern instrument building. There are so many quality instruments being offered by so many great builders (both large and small) that the options are really overwhelming. Beyond all the familiar big names and the many popular smaller builders, the quality of instruments coming out of the East has been on the rise for the past 30 years as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milkman 5W Half Pint Head with Mather Cab in Walnut </title>
      <link>/journal/2022/02/07/milkman-half-pint-walnut-head-mather-cab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/02/07/milkman-half-pint-walnut-head-mather-cab/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;ve dug through the archived journal entries here or seen my Instagram feed you know that I&#39;ve owned a lot of Mesa Boogie amps and cabs. I love the way they sound and love that they are made in California, but I always ran into two problems. One, they are universally very heavy amps. That&#39;s not a terrible thing if you want something really well made and road worthy, but my gear doesn&#39;t move around too much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1999 Taylor/Klein Imbuia AB-2 Acoustic Bass Guitar</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/09/22/1999-taylor-klein-ab-2-imbuia-acoustic-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/09/22/1999-taylor-klein-ab-2-imbuia-acoustic-bass/</guid>
      <description>I picked this up recently after about 20 years of wanting one. It&#39;s absolutely the nicest acoustic bass guitar I have played... but after owning it for a few weeks I think it is actually a little too nice for me. Oddly enough after so long waiting I lucked into a good deal on an another one of these (AB-1) that needs some work. I am going to let this one go and keep the one that needs some work as I am more of a tweaker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1976 Mesa Boogie Mark I Combo - Factory Upgraded Simul-class DRG</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/04/14/padauk-mesa-boogie-mark-i-1976-drg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/04/14/padauk-mesa-boogie-mark-i-1976-drg/</guid>
      <description>This is a pretty special Mesa Boogie Mark I. It is an original Mark I, serial A802, and was made in late 1976. Just two amps before Keith Richard&#39;s legendary A804! This was originally a 100/60w amp, then factory upgraded to Simul-class in the mid eighties (transformer code is 1985). This upgrade work was confirmed to be factory performed when the amp was sent back to Mesa for a full service and cap job in April 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark IIB Coliseum Padauk Hardwood &amp; Wicker Big Brother</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/04/14/padauk-mesa-boogie-iib-coliseum-big-brother/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/04/14/padauk-mesa-boogie-iib-coliseum-big-brother/</guid>
      <description>This is a Mesa Boogie Mark IIB Coliseum, also known as the &#34;Series 300&#34;. It&#39;s a KG which mean switchable Coliseum 180-watt power section (K) and Graphic EQ (G) options are present. The speaker is an Electro-Voice EVM-15L. The included power tubes are very hard to find STR-415s as would have been included back in the 80s. Serial is K238. This amp was originally housed in a black bronco headshell, but was recently moved into this original Mesa Padauk hardwood &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1994 Mesa Boogie Imbuia &amp; Wicker Half-Back Speaker Cab</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/01/08/mesa-boogie-imbuia-half-back-cabinet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/01/08/mesa-boogie-imbuia-half-back-cabinet/</guid>
      <description>This is a beautiful hardwood &amp; wicker speaker cabinet from Mesa Engineering. It&#39;s a half-back with an EVM-12L from 1994. Between the year and the logo plate this looks like something that would have been bundled with a Mark IV. I can see from inside that at some point a speaker was rear mounted in this cab. Based on the foam left behind I would guess it was a C90. Around this time an EVM-12L would have the black sticker so this may be an older non-original speaker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coilton the Accuwinder CW-11B Coil Winding Machine</title>
      <link>/journal/2018/11/18/accuwinder-pickup-winder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2018/11/18/accuwinder-pickup-winder/</guid>
      <description>This was a serendipitous find. Years ago my therapist suggested I spend more idle time in the evening without a digital device in front of me. It took a while before I gave it a fair shot, but upon trying it out my mind started filling up with new ideas almost immediately. Very quickly it became obvious I needed a pickup winder to start working through some of these ideas. I had looked at buying winders before but they always felt fairly expensive for the limited functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1990 Boire Warwick Dolphin Pro I Bass</title>
      <link>/journal/2018/05/09/boire-warwick-dolphin-pro-1-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2018/05/09/boire-warwick-dolphin-pro-1-bass/</guid>
      <description>This is a no-compromise early Warwick Dolphin Pro I with all the best features. Being a 1990 it&#39;s still in the Warwick &#34;handmade&#34; era. It has the coveted Boire Rosewood body instead of the later Ovangkol. Bartolini J+MM Pickups and 2-Band Pre-amp instead of later MEC. Satin Chrome (also called titanium or platinum) hardware including Schaller strap locks. 7-piece Wenge/Zebrano neck WITHOUT the volute like the later Dolphins. No modifications, missing pieces, or weird custom features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Imbuia Hardwood &amp; Wicker Thiele Ported Compact Cab</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/11/25/mesa-boogie-imbuia-thiele-ported-cab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/11/25/mesa-boogie-imbuia-thiele-ported-cab/</guid>
      <description>This is the Holy Grail of Mesa cabs, a vintage hardwood &amp; wicker Thiele compact cab with the original EVM-12L. This one is in Imbuia and the figure is gorgeous. Judging from the logo plate and jack style I would guess this is from the mid to late eighties. The condition is solid, but a little rough around the edges. Someone definitely loved this cab and got a lot of use out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark IIC&#43; Simul-Class, GEQ, Hardwood Medium Head</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/09/06/mesa-boogie-mark-iic-plus-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/09/06/mesa-boogie-mark-iic-plus-head/</guid>
      <description>This is a holy grail kind of amp on multiple fronts. IIC+/Simul-Class/GEQ is the most desired vintage Boogie by far, and for the hardwood fans these medium head shells in hardwood/wicker are almost never to be found, and the 415/416 power tube combo is the best for vintage Simul-Class Boogies. STR-415s are not common, but STR-416s have become VERY rare. On top of that, we have all the original paperwork. The tubes are tested and matching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Lone Star Special Tasmanian Blackwood Hardwood Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/09/04/tasmanian-blackwood-mesa-boogie-lone-star-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/09/04/tasmanian-blackwood-mesa-boogie-lone-star-special/</guid>
      <description>This Mesa Boogie Lone Star Special features a fairly uncommon Tasmanian Blackwood hardwood combo cabinet.
Lots of tonal options and the great MC-90 speaker. Another one that got away but you can&#39;t keep them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark III/IIC&#43; Red Stripe Head, Simul-Class, GEQ</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/05/20/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-c-plus-head-drg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/05/20/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-c-plus-head-drg/</guid>
      <description>Mesa Boogie Mark III Red Stripe Head, Simul-Class, GEQ, IIC+/III+ Upgrade, All Mods, Hardwood/Wicker This is a 1987 Mesa Boogie Mark III Head. It&#39;s a Red Stripe version. It&#39;s fully loaded with Graphic EQ, Reverb, and Simul-class. It&#39;s also fully loaded in that it has the IIC+/III+ Upgrade, Reverb Fix, R2 Volume Mod, and a Triode/Pentode switch which you don&#39;t often see on these. That is just about every feature you can expect to find on a Mark III.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1981 Imbuia Hardwood &amp; Wicker Mesa Boogie Mark IIB Combo Amp</title>
      <link>/journal/2016/08/26/padauk-mesa-boogie-mark-iib/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2016/08/26/padauk-mesa-boogie-mark-iib/</guid>
      <description>This is a beautiful 1981 Mesa Boogie Mark IIB combo. As far as I know/understand this amp is in completetly original.
It is in very nice condition, especially when you consider it is 35
years old. I contacted Mesa Boogie support and they think this cabinet is made from imbuya. That seems to be par for the
course for this era, but this certainly has more contrast in the grain than a lot of others I have seen listed as</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Padauk Hardwood &amp; Wicker Thiele Ported Cab Set</title>
      <link>/journal/2016/08/26/padauk-mesa-boogie-thiele/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2016/08/26/padauk-mesa-boogie-thiele/</guid>
      <description>This is the Holy Grail of Mesa cabs, a vintage hardwood &amp;amp; wicker Thiele with original EVM-12L from 1986. When you
consider this thing is around 30 years old it is in great shape. It was made using amazing 13&#34; wide padauk boards. The
condition is pretty good, but all the patina is also perfect to match a Mark head or combo from the era. I have
been looking for one of these for quite a while and was lucky enough to find an original matching pair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1993 Imbuia Hardwood &amp; Wicker Mesa Boogie Mark IV Compact Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2014/12/07/imbuia-mesa-boogie-mark-iv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2014/12/07/imbuia-mesa-boogie-mark-iv/</guid>
      <description>Here is a beautiful Mark IV from 1993. This is the &#34;A&#34; version which can be distinguished by the attached power cord and lack of foot switchable reverb.
The upside to the &#34;A&#34; version amps is the lead
channel voicing is closer to the original IIC+. This is a imbuia wood cabinet with wicker grill and it is the &#34;compact&#34;
cab size. The great looks and small size makes for a perfect living room combo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SF3co: Eco Friendly Guitar</title>
      <link>/journal/2010/11/07/sf3co-eco-friendly-electric-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2010/11/07/sf3co-eco-friendly-electric-guitar/</guid>
      <description>The most important thing to do in your life is to not interfere with somebody else&#39;s life.
 Frank Zappa   I doubt Zappa had any kind of ecological issues in mind when he said this but I&#39;ll happily quote one of my heroes when his words sum up my feelings so perfectly. Background: The Problem When I first became interested in guitars and music I had no idea where the materials for new instruments came from or who made them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
