<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Scott French</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>July 2023 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2023/07/31/july-2023-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2023/07/31/july-2023-update/</guid>
      <description>July came and went in a flash. At the start of the month I spent some time building a flexible side-dot drilling jig and toward the end of the month I started roughing out the neck heel and headstock. More photos of the progress at the instrument page below. Chambered Claro Walnut SF3 Carve Top Guitar The side-dot jig is pretty simple... it&#39;s a carrier to mount the fingerboard and hold replaceable acrylic templates for different scale lengths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023 First Half Recap</title>
      <link>/journal/2023/07/04/2023-first-half-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2023/07/04/2023-first-half-recap/</guid>
      <description>The May and June Update ended up being so big that there wasn&#39;t much room left, but being that we&#39;re half way through 2023 I wanted to reflect a bit on the year so far. Just a little background, at the very start of 2022 I made the decision to really focus on getting back into luthiery. I had been playing with it since around 2018, but a lot of competing ideas meant there wasn&#39;t much forward progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May and June 2023 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2023/06/30/may-june-2023-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2023/06/30/may-june-2023-update/</guid>
      <description>This journal was intended to be updated monthly, but here we are with back-to-back entries spanning two full months each. I should be back on the monthly schedule going forward. One more note before moving into the actual update... I had planned on attending the 2023 GAL Convention this upcoming week, but when I starting really looking at my current progress and funds, I decided it would be better to spend that time and money working on an actual guitar instead of going on a trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March and April 2023 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2023/04/17/march-april-2023-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2023/04/17/march-april-2023-update/</guid>
      <description>March started slow with sickness and bad weather, then ended with even more snow. Throughout the month I continued making progress on digitizing the SF3 design into 3D for future CAD/CAM options. For now I will be doing a lot of the work on this next SF3 by hand because I don&#39;t want to waste any of this good weather on the computer. Speaking of the new SF3, there is some new progress here and at the project page below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February 2023 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2023/02/28/february-2023-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2023/02/28/february-2023-update/</guid>
      <description>February started with a bang and ended with a whimper. All of January&#39;s forward progress carried over to the new month with several objects being modelled and machined. I refined the pickup cover design a bit and also moved into the recessed pickup rings. From there I made some good progress on a two-piece knob design. Here&#39;s a short video showing how quick you&#39;re able to take an idea from paper to a physical object with all these awesome modern tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 2023 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2023/01/31/january-2023-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2023/01/31/january-2023-update/</guid>
      <description>January was a great month full of learning, and as a result some new progress was made on the next SF3! I&#39;ve wanted to learn 3D CAD/CAM for many years but have always been intimidated by the complexity. It was a great moment when I found out that I could do simple 2.5D CAD/CAM using Illustrator SVGs when I first got the CNC. Being able to work with software and concepts that I was already familiar with was great because it allowed me focused on the initial challenge of learning how to run a CNC and use basic CAD/CAM software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>December 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/12/30/december-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/12/30/december-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>The last few months of the year are always busy around here. Holidays, birthdays, anniversaries, school events, and end-of-year work always means there is no free time. It&#39;s been a great and full year for my family so I have no complaints, but I have not been able to touch anything guitar related in some time. I&#39;m coming into the New Year with even more focus than last year, so I&#39;m excited for the coming months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/11/21/november-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/11/21/november-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>Fall is upon us and another busy time of year has come again. I missed the October website update and November is almost over! In October my family got a new Great Dane puppy named Juno. For now she&#39;s a lot of work (and puppies can be quite annoying), but we&#39;re looking forward to her being a great companion to our older Dane, Freya. Lots of family joy celebrating the new crew member and learning how to best take care of her together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/09/22/september-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/09/22/september-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick update for September. I&#39;ve added a few new backlogged journal updates with more old Boogie photos as well as a very strange Atlansia instrument. Check those out here: 1994 Atlansia Solitaire Single String Bass
Mesa Boogie Dual Rectifier Trem-o-verb Hardwood Combo
Mesa Boogie Collection Odds and Ends On the topic of the new SF3, it is moving along slowly but steadily. The plans are nearly done and I have made some solid progress in getting the new pickups all sorted and ready to start building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1994 Atlansia Solitaire Single String Bass</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/09/21/1994-atlansia-solitaire-single-string-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/09/21/1994-atlansia-solitaire-single-string-bass/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned on the Inspiration page of this site, Atlansia has been one of my favorite builders for a long time. These instruments so rarely show up in the US that I didn&#39;t think long when I saw this one pop up for sale in Japan with US shipping as an option. Even with slow COVID shipping from Japan it was still worth it. I ordered it mostly to check out all the interesting features so I will likely move it along somewhat soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Collection Odds and Ends</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/09/15/mesa-boogie-collection-odds-and-ends/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/09/15/mesa-boogie-collection-odds-and-ends/</guid>
      <description>These are all the random Boogie photos that don&#39;t fit anywhere else. Lots of hardwood combos, Big Brothers, and Thieles... Oh my! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/08/31/august-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/08/31/august-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>All things considered August was a good month on the guitar front. I started the month working on my first ever pedalboard. I have been collecting parts and planning for years but it&#39;s finally time to put it all together. Almost immediately I ran into shipping delays on some essential parts so the project is currently on hold, but I hope to finish the first version in September if there are no more delays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chambered Claro Walnut SF3 Carve Top Guitar</title>
      <link>/in-progress/chambered-claro-walnut-sf3-carve-top-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/in-progress/chambered-claro-walnut-sf3-carve-top-guitar/</guid>
      <description>The first step toward a new generation of SF3 Guitars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/07/06/july-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/07/06/july-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>For anyone paying attention, you probably noticed that June came and went without an update. The reason is pretty simple, I didn&#39;t really do anything guitar related in June. School ended and my kids started their summer break. I got on a plane for the first time in fifteen years and we all took a trip to Nashville and Atlanta. We had a lot of fun there, Nashville is an interesting place and there&#39;s lots of guitar content all over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspiration</title>
      <link>/inspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/inspiration/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/05/28/may-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/05/28/may-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>Before I launched this new site in April my hope was I would be able to to make a new journal entry each week, but during the process of getting the site finished and released I realized once per month was much more likely. April was a busy month with my wife Brianna away most of the time working a new mural. May turned out to be just as busy with several small building projects, an overnight class field trip, and lots of other family, work, and house projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Pickup for Christian Allen Luthiery</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/05/24/custom-pickup-christian-allen-luthiery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/05/24/custom-pickup-christian-allen-luthiery/</guid>
      <description>Christian is a great local luthier and fellow Roberto-Venn graduate. He&#39;s been building some really interesting instruments recently and this is the third custom pickup I&#39;ve made for him. For this project he needed a magnetic humbucking pickup to cover only three closely spaced strings. This post gives you an idea of how these projects can go. I recieve some basic dimensions from Christian, then digitize those in Adobe Illustrator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Website for 2022</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/04/10/website-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/04/10/website-updates/</guid>
      <description>Hello! Thanks for reading this. Building a new website has been a long time coming. I guess you could think of it as a more serious step in my eventual return to lutherie. I&#39;ve been away from guitar building in any productive capacity since around 2008. I have worked on some projects since then, but not a lot since 2011. Around 2018 I was in therapy working through a particularly tough time in my life, and going through that process really reawakened the desire to build instruments again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto of an Electric Guitar Builder</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/04/09/manifesto-of-an-electric-guitar-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/04/09/manifesto-of-an-electric-guitar-builder/</guid>
      <description>The previous entry in this four part series found me questioning some long held beliefs around the value of handmade instruments and making the decision to use all the modern tools available to me. This final entry outlines some of the other important choices that help shape my instruments. 
There&#39;s a famous document in the software world that was authored and co-signed by many of the most influential developers in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Handmade Question</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/04/02/the-handmade-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/04/02/the-handmade-question/</guid>
      <description>The previous entry in this four part series found me reconnecting with the parts of lutherie that inspired me from the start and deciding to move forward with guitar building in ways I never considered. This entry is an extension of that reconsideration of all things held holy in guitar building. 
If you went back and looked at my first website from 2004, you&#39;d see I put a lot of emphasis on my instruments being handmade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconnecting With Inspiration</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/03/26/reconnecting-with-inspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/03/26/reconnecting-with-inspiration/</guid>
      <description>The previous entry in this four part series found me questioning my place in the guitar world and eventually leaving to pursue other endeavors. We pick up almost ten years later when my therapist encouraged me to revisit lutherie looking for some long lost seeds of joy. 
I never really stopped thinking about guitars during the time I was away, but with work and family all I really had time for in the guitar world was thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Age Of Lutherie</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/03/19/the-golden-age-of-lutherie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/03/19/the-golden-age-of-lutherie/</guid>
      <description>We&#39;re living through what is often called The Golden Age of Lutherie. Whereas in the past luthiers and large companies tended to guard their secrets, we&#39;ve seen an explosion of communication and information sharing that&#39;s raised the standard for modern instrument building. There are so many quality instruments being offered by so many great builders (both large and small) that the options are really overwhelming. Beyond all the familiar big names and the many popular smaller builders, the quality of instruments coming out of the East has been on the rise for the past 30 years as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milkman 5W Half Pint Head with Mather Cab in Walnut </title>
      <link>/journal/2022/02/07/milkman-half-pint-walnut-head-mather-cab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/02/07/milkman-half-pint-walnut-head-mather-cab/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;ve dug through the archived journal entries here or seen my Instagram feed you know that I&#39;ve owned a lot of Mesa Boogie amps and cabs. I love the way they sound and love that they are made in California, but I always ran into two problems. One, they are universally very heavy amps. That&#39;s not a terrible thing if you want something really well made and road worthy, but my gear doesn&#39;t move around too much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy</title>
      <link>/philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/philosophy/</guid>
      <description>I started writing this as one big page outlining my outlook on instrument building and how I got here, but it grew so large and so personal that I decided to break it up into multiple journal entries. I&#39;ll warn you, the first two entries are more about me and my journey, but they help set the stage for the second two entries. If you want to get right into the details about instruments I&#39;d suggest skipping to the last entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Hello weary web traveller!
Thanks for visiting my site. Here in 2022 and beyond I have to commend you on being a true web explorer. With the current consolidation of all information being shared across so few platforms, it&#39;s more important than ever to expand your search in the gathering of information. Please understand when I say &#34;thanks for visiting&#34; it is more than a perfunctory statement. I truly appreciate that you have found my home on the internet and decided to visit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I&#39;m Scott French, a guitar builder and software developer from Northern California. This page is just about me, if you&#39;re interested in learning about my approach to instrument building please check out the Philosophy page instead. The early years I was born in The Capital of Silicon Valley, San Jose in the early 80s. My family later relocated to the Sierra Foothills where I still reside with my own family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Dual Rectifier Trem-o-verb 2x12 Hardwood &amp; Wicker Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2021/08/09/mesa-boogie-trem-o-verb-2x12-hardwood-combo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2021/08/09/mesa-boogie-trem-o-verb-2x12-hardwood-combo/</guid>
      <description>This is an early Dual Rectifier in the Trem-o-verb trim. 100-watt combo with two 12&#34; Celestion Vintage 30s. The cab is a beautiful hardwood... I believe it is Imbuia but there are no markings inside. The original grill was wheat, but I had Mesa Boogie build me a new one in wicker cane a few years back. Power tubes are a matched set of vintage Sylvania GC6L6s (STR-415). This is a weird one in that I&#39;ve never seen another hardwood Trem-o-verb head or combo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Imbuia &amp; Wicker Thiele Compact Ported Cab</title>
      <link>/journal/2021/01/04/mesa-boogie-thiele-imbuia-cabinet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2021/01/04/mesa-boogie-thiele-imbuia-cabinet/</guid>
      <description>This is the Holy Grail of Mesa cabs, a vintage hardwood &amp; wicker Thiele with Electro-Voice EVM-12L from 1987. When you consider this thing is over 30 years old it is in pretty nice shape. It was made using amazing 13&#34; wide imbuia boards. Condition is pretty nice overall. There are dents and dings throughout, but overall it presents pretty well. Weight is 48lbs. I&#39;ve purchased this cab twice and both times it was poorly packaged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1999 Taylor/Klein Imbuia AB-2 Acoustic Bass Guitar</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/09/22/1999-taylor-klein-ab-2-imbuia-acoustic-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/09/22/1999-taylor-klein-ab-2-imbuia-acoustic-bass/</guid>
      <description>I picked this up recently after about 20 years of wanting one. It&#39;s absolutely the nicest acoustic bass guitar I have played... but after owning it for a few weeks I think it is actually a little too nice for me. Oddly enough after so long waiting I lucked into a good deal on an another one of these (AB-1) that needs some work. I am going to let this one go and keep the one that needs some work as I am more of a tweaker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1976 Mesa Boogie Mark I Combo - Factory Upgraded Simul-class DRG</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/04/14/padauk-mesa-boogie-mark-i-1976-drg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/04/14/padauk-mesa-boogie-mark-i-1976-drg/</guid>
      <description>This is a pretty special Mesa Boogie Mark I. It is an original Mark I, serial A802, and was made in late 1976. Just two amps before Keith Richard&#39;s legendary A804! This was originally a 100/60w amp, then factory upgraded to Simul-class in the mid eighties (transformer code is 1985). This upgrade work was confirmed to be factory performed when the amp was sent back to Mesa for a full service and cap job in April 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark IIB Coliseum Padauk Hardwood &amp; Wicker Big Brother</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/04/14/padauk-mesa-boogie-iib-coliseum-big-brother/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/04/14/padauk-mesa-boogie-iib-coliseum-big-brother/</guid>
      <description>This is a Mesa Boogie Mark IIB Coliseum, also known as the &#34;Series 300&#34;. It&#39;s a KG which mean switchable Coliseum 180-watt power section (K) and Graphic EQ (G) options are present. The speaker is an Electro-Voice EVM-15L. The included power tubes are very hard to find STR-415s as would have been included back in the 80s. Serial is K238. This amp was originally housed in a black bronco headshell, but was recently moved into this original Mesa Padauk hardwood &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Hardwood &amp; Wicker Dual Rectifier Blue Angel 2x10&#34; Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/04/04/mesa-boogie-hardwood-dual-rectifier-blue-angel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/04/04/mesa-boogie-hardwood-dual-rectifier-blue-angel/</guid>
      <description>This Blue Angel combo is a really cool and very un-Mesa like amp. I don&#39;t think they ever made and another 2x10&#34; as far as I remember and to find one in hardwood was an amazing surprise. There are no markings inside, but if I had to guess I would say it is Imbuia. The power section of this amp mixing tube types with switchable combinations is also very strange and worth looking into if you&#39;re interested in something different for Mesa Boogie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark III / IIIC&#43; with 105PT &amp; STR-415/416 Imbuia</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/03/29/mesa-boogie-mark-iiic-plus-drg-imbuia-combo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/03/29/mesa-boogie-mark-iiic-plus-drg-imbuia-combo/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;re looking for the best possible Mark III then you can stop here, you&#39;ve found it. This is a 1985 Mesa Boogie Mark III. It&#39;s an early no-stripe version released just after the Mark IIC+, and being a transition model they share a few common elements. The 105 power transformer and heavier faceplate are carried over from the IIC+. This is a DRG, meaning Simul-class, Reverb, and Graphic EQ options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Thiele Ported Compact Cab in Imbuia Hardwood &amp; Wicker</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/01/09/mesa-boogie-thiele-cabinet-imbuia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/01/09/mesa-boogie-thiele-cabinet-imbuia/</guid>
      <description>This is the Holy Grail of Mesa cabs, a vintage hardwood &amp; wicker Thiele with EVM-12L from the Mark III era. When you consider this thing is around 30 years old it is in pretty nice shape. It was made using amazing 13&#34; wide imbuia boards. Condition is pretty nice overall. There are dents and dings throughout, and also some substantial scratches on top from amp feet. The speaker and it has a 1989 date code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1994 Mesa Boogie Imbuia &amp; Wicker Half-Back Speaker Cab</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/01/08/mesa-boogie-imbuia-half-back-cabinet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/01/08/mesa-boogie-imbuia-half-back-cabinet/</guid>
      <description>This is a beautiful hardwood &amp; wicker speaker cabinet from Mesa Engineering. It&#39;s a half-back with an EVM-12L from 1994. Between the year and the logo plate this looks like something that would have been bundled with a Mark IV. I can see from inside that at some point a speaker was rear mounted in this cab. Based on the foam left behind I would guess it was a C90. Around this time an EVM-12L would have the black sticker so this may be an older non-original speaker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coilton the Accuwinder CW-11B Coil Winding Machine</title>
      <link>/journal/2018/11/18/accuwinder-pickup-winder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2018/11/18/accuwinder-pickup-winder/</guid>
      <description>This was a serendipitous find. Years ago my therapist suggested I spend more idle time in the evening without a digital device in front of me. It took a while before I gave it a fair shot, but upon trying it out my mind started filling up with new ideas almost immediately. Very quickly it became obvious I needed a pickup winder to start working through some of these ideas. I had looked at buying winders before but they always felt fairly expensive for the limited functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1990 Boire Warwick Dolphin Pro I Bass</title>
      <link>/journal/2018/05/09/boire-warwick-dolphin-pro-1-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2018/05/09/boire-warwick-dolphin-pro-1-bass/</guid>
      <description>This is a no-compromise early Warwick Dolphin Pro I with all the best features. Being a 1990 it&#39;s still in the Warwick &#34;handmade&#34; era. It has the coveted Boire Rosewood body instead of the later Ovangkol. Bartolini J+MM Pickups and 2-Band Pre-amp instead of later MEC. Satin Chrome (also called titanium or platinum) hardware including Schaller strap locks. 7-piece Wenge/Zebrano neck WITHOUT the volute like the later Dolphins. No modifications, missing pieces, or weird custom features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Padauk &amp; Wicker Half-Back Speaker Cabinet</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/12/24/mesa-boogie-padauk-half-back-cabinet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/12/24/mesa-boogie-padauk-half-back-cabinet/</guid>
      <description>This is a beautiful Mesa speaker cabinet, a vintage hardwood &amp; wicker half-back with original EVM-12L from the early 80s. When you consider this thing is around 35 years old it is in almost perfect shape. It was made using amazing 11&#34; wide boards. Based on the grain and era I think this may be padauk. There are no factory markings inside the cab but based on the logo plate and jack mount it looks to be from the Mark II/IIB/IIC/IIC+ era.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Imbuia Hardwood &amp; Wicker Thiele Ported Compact Cab</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/11/25/mesa-boogie-imbuia-thiele-ported-cab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/11/25/mesa-boogie-imbuia-thiele-ported-cab/</guid>
      <description>This is the Holy Grail of Mesa cabs, a vintage hardwood &amp; wicker Thiele compact cab with the original EVM-12L. This one is in Imbuia and the figure is gorgeous. Judging from the logo plate and jack style I would guess this is from the mid to late eighties. The condition is solid, but a little rough around the edges. Someone definitely loved this cab and got a lot of use out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark IIC&#43; Simul-Class, GEQ, Hardwood Medium Head</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/09/06/mesa-boogie-mark-iic-plus-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/09/06/mesa-boogie-mark-iic-plus-head/</guid>
      <description>This is a holy grail kind of amp on multiple fronts. IIC+/Simul-Class/GEQ is the most desired vintage Boogie by far, and for the hardwood fans these medium head shells in hardwood/wicker are almost never to be found, and the 415/416 power tube combo is the best for vintage Simul-Class Boogies. STR-415s are not common, but STR-416s have become VERY rare. On top of that, we have all the original paperwork. The tubes are tested and matching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Lone Star Special Tasmanian Blackwood Hardwood Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/09/04/tasmanian-blackwood-mesa-boogie-lone-star-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/09/04/tasmanian-blackwood-mesa-boogie-lone-star-special/</guid>
      <description>This Mesa Boogie Lone Star Special features a fairly uncommon Tasmanian Blackwood hardwood combo cabinet.
Lots of tonal options and the great MC-90 speaker. Another one that got away but you can&#39;t keep them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark III Black Stripe DRG Imbuia Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/09/03/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-black-stripe-drg-imbuia-combo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/09/03/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-black-stripe-drg-imbuia-combo/</guid>
      <description>This is a 1985 MESA/Boogie Mark III Combo. It is a DRG model, which means Simul-Class power section, Reverb, and Graphic EQ. This is a black/no-stripe revision which is the first of the Mark IIIs. Some early black/no-stripe examples share several features with the Mark IIC+. First, this amp has the early-style etched face plate where all the lines and text are metal instead of white paint. These hold up a lot better than the painted face plates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark III/IIC&#43; Red Stripe Head, Simul-Class, GEQ</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/05/20/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-c-plus-head-drg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/05/20/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-c-plus-head-drg/</guid>
      <description>This is a 1987 Mesa Boogie Mark III Head. It&#39;s the Red Stripe version. It&#39;s fully loaded with Graphic EQ, Reverb, and Simul-class. It&#39;s also fully loaded in that it has the IIC+/III+ Upgrade, Reverb Fix, R2 Volume Mod, and a Triode/Pentode switch which you don&#39;t often see on these. That is just about every feature you can expect to find on a Mark III. On top of that, it comes in a beautiful Hardwood and Wicker headshell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark III Blue Stripe DRG Imbuia Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/03/14/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-blue-stripe-drg-imbuia-combo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/03/14/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-blue-stripe-drg-imbuia-combo/</guid>
      <description>You&#39;re looking at a 1988 Mesa Boogie Mark III Blue Stripe Combo. It is a DRG, meaning Simul-class power, Reverb, and Graphic EQ. It also has an Electro-Voice EVM-12L 12&#34; speaker. The cabinet is unmarked, but it looks like other cabinets I&#39;ve had that were marked Imbuia. This is basically a fully loaded Mark III with all the preferred features. On top of all that, it already has the factory R2 volume mod and reverb fix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Hardwood &amp; Wicker Mark IIC Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/01/17/mesa-boogie-hardwood-wicker-mark-iic-combo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/01/17/mesa-boogie-hardwood-wicker-mark-iic-combo/</guid>
      <description>This is a very clean Mark IIC in its original hardwood &amp; wicker cabinet. It&#39;s a 60 watt model with reverb. The speaker is a Mesa/Celestion Black Shadow MC-90. I am not sure the wood species, but it does seem to fit in with other hardwood Mark series amps of this era. My guess would be padauk. When I purchased this amp I was told it had a recent service/cleaning including new caps and power cord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark III Purple Stripe DRG Imbuia Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2016/10/20/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-purple-stripe-drg-imbuia-combo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2016/10/20/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-purple-stripe-drg-imbuia-combo/</guid>
      <description>This is a 1986 Mesa Boogie Mark III Purple Stripe Combo in Imbuya and Wicker. As far as I know this amp is 100% original. Features include Graphic EQ, Reverb, and Simul-Class which would make this a DRG. Also includes the iconic Electro Voice EVM-12L speaker. Chassis mount is SUS-4. Original vinyl cover is quite worn out. Does the job but doesn&#39;t look very good. You can judge the condition for yourself based on the photos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1981 Imbuia Hardwood &amp; Wicker Mesa Boogie Mark IIB Combo Amp</title>
      <link>/journal/2016/08/26/padauk-mesa-boogie-mark-iib/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2016/08/26/padauk-mesa-boogie-mark-iib/</guid>
      <description>This is a beautiful 1981 Mesa Boogie Mark IIB combo. As far as I know/understand this amp is in completetly original.
It is in very nice condition, especially when you consider it is 35
years old. I contacted Mesa Boogie support and they think this cabinet is made from imbuya. That seems to be par for the
course for this era, but this certainly has more contrast in the grain than a lot of others I have seen listed as</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Padauk Hardwood &amp; Wicker Thiele Ported Cab Set</title>
      <link>/journal/2016/08/26/padauk-mesa-boogie-thiele/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2016/08/26/padauk-mesa-boogie-thiele/</guid>
      <description>This is the Holy Grail of Mesa cabs, a vintage hardwood &amp;amp; wicker Thiele with original EVM-12L from 1986. When you
consider this thing is around 30 years old it is in great shape. It was made using amazing 13&#34; wide padauk boards. The
condition is pretty good, but all the patina is also perfect to match a Mark head or combo from the era. I have
been looking for one of these for quite a while and was lucky enough to find an original matching pair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1993 Imbuia Hardwood &amp; Wicker Mesa Boogie Mark IV Compact Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2014/12/07/imbuia-mesa-boogie-mark-iv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2014/12/07/imbuia-mesa-boogie-mark-iv/</guid>
      <description>Here is a beautiful Mark IV from 1993. This is the &#34;A&#34; version which can be distinguished by the attached power cord and lack of foot switchable reverb.
The upside to the &#34;A&#34; version amps is the lead
channel voicing is closer to the original IIC+. This is a imbuia wood cabinet with wicker grill and it is the &#34;compact&#34;
cab size. The great looks and small size makes for a perfect living room combo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SF3co Eco Guitar Prototype</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3co-eco-guitar-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3co-eco-guitar-prototype/</guid>
      <description>I started this prototype and the potential line of instruments it represented after taking a break from lutherie. It marked a shift in how I think about guitars and how I go about working on a project. Even though it was ultimately not a success, I did learn a lot about doing things I actually care about. The response to this instrument from potential customers was very strong and the fact that I didn&#39;t build a ton of them for excited customers really has more to do with my own personal situation starting a family and nothing to do with players&#39; appetite for &#39;alternative&#39; instruments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redwood SF2 Chambered Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/redwood-sf2-chambered-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/redwood-sf2-chambered-guitar/</guid>
      <description>I could write a lot about this guitar, but ultimately I&#39;ll just say that trying to finish the burl redwood I used for the top
had me questioning my choice to ever get involved with guitar building. In the end, finish problems aside this guitar ended
up being pretty cool and sounding really good. The SF2 is a scaled down acoustic guitar design, but really it is too
traditional for me at this point and I doubt I will go any further down this path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SF3co: Eco Friendly Guitar</title>
      <link>/journal/2010/11/07/sf3co-eco-friendly-electric-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2010/11/07/sf3co-eco-friendly-electric-guitar/</guid>
      <description>The most important thing to do in your life is to not interfere with somebody else&#39;s life.
 Frank Zappa   I doubt Zappa had any kind of ecological issues in mind when he said this but I&#39;ll happily quote one of my heroes when his words sum up my feelings so perfectly. Background: The Problem When I first became interested in guitars and music I had no idea where the materials for new instruments came from or who made them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buckeye Burl SF3 Singlecut Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/buckeye-burl-sf3-singlecut-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/buckeye-burl-sf3-singlecut-guitar/</guid>
      <description>My friend Ian called one day and let me know our local Salvation Army had an absolute unit of a buckeye burl table come in that week.
I dropped everything to go look and it ended up being several burls combined into one table using about 40 pounds of epoxy and fiberglass.
We ruined a chainsaw blade and bandsaw blade just getting this one blank out of the table, but it was well worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Paisley SF3 Leo Fender Tribute Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/pink-paisley-sf3-leo-fender-tribute-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/pink-paisley-sf3-leo-fender-tribute-guitar/</guid>
      <description>I built this guitar as a tribute to Leo Fender. Like every gutiar builder ever I love his material choices, simple solutions,
and timeless designs. I didn&#39;t want to lean all the way into the vintage trap though so I included some crazy 18v active
pickups. If I built this one again I would do an oiled &amp;amp; waxed bolt-on neck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claro Walnut SF3 Singlecut Bass Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This was the rare instrument I actuatlly built on spec and the whole thing just went quick and easy.
I lucked into this beautiful and THICK Claro Walnut body blank that just perfectly fit with this 
singlecut SF3 bodystyle. I already had all the hardware and electronics around so this project came together
in a matter of days. It ended up going to local person with some interesting stories and a great instrument</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redwood &amp; Maple SF3 Bowable Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/redwood-maple-sf3-bowable-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/redwood-maple-sf3-bowable-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This SF3 came with a fairly straightforward goal: to be easy to play with a bow.
Narrowing the SF3 design and doing an exagerated top carve ended up being the easy part...
findings pickups and a bridge to accomodate that extreme radius was more challenging.
Nordstrand was able to supply some custom NDC humbuckers with super staggered magnets for the pickups.
For the bridge I used Graphtech saddles and built a very custom ebony bridge by hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myrtle Burl SF3 Chambered Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/myrtle-burl-sf3-chambered-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/myrtle-burl-sf3-chambered-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This is another fun SF3 with further refinements of the bodyshape. I found the one-piece top on a road trip in the Pacific Northwest. Lots of nice bloodwood details on this one that pair really well with the myrtle. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenge &amp; Mahogany SF3 Chambered Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/wenge-mahogany-sf3-chambered-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/wenge-mahogany-sf3-chambered-guitar/</guid>
      <description>There was a time when it was very hard to find to find wenge locally so I generally grabbed
it whenever it did show up. With that spirit one day I visited my most local, small town lumber
store and found some HUGE wenge slabs with plenty of space for multiple one-piece tops. I bought
all the clean boards and have been using them ever since. For me this guitar really was all</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Limba &amp; Rosewood SF3 Chambered Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/black-limba-rosewood-sf3-chambered-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/black-limba-rosewood-sf3-chambered-guitar/</guid>
      <description>I don&#39;t generally aim for using woods that compeltely steal the show, but even with subdued blanks I feel
like that&#39;s what ended up happening here. This black limba top and rosewood neck combo just really popped and
everything came together nicely. This is a great build to highlight how material selection and more importantly
a creative cut list can really impact the outcome. My memory is this was was originally a one-piece flat-sawn</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myrtle &amp; Redwood SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/myrtle-redwood-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/myrtle-redwood-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This SF3 represents a big transition with the design of the headstock and heel being refinfed
quite a bit. It was also a really light one thanks to the chambered redwood body and myrtle top. 
The redwood came from a thrift shop table and the myrtle from a Pacific Northwest road trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bolivian Rosewood &amp; Butternut SF3 Travel Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/rosewood-butternut-sf3-travel-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/rosewood-butternut-sf3-travel-guitar/</guid>
      <description>I don&#39;t have any stats to back this up, but I am fairly certain this was my most popular
guitar. I still get random emails from people looking to pick one up. I&#39;m really happy with
the design and how the guitar turned out, but the Steinberger tuners are a little wonky so I was 
always considering different options for future travel guitars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headless SF3 Singlecut Synth Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/headless-sf3-singlecut-synth-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/headless-sf3-singlecut-synth-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This was a fun project with a lot of elements I had never worked with before. The active pickups and Roland synth setup were interesting and the headless hardware worked out well. This did inspire me to want to work on a more elegant headless setup as the hardware was a bit industrial in design and feel. All the black parts and the heavy headless hardware definitely gave this one a unique feel within my body of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gum Eucalyptus SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This guitar came about when I lucked into two really nice pieces of local wood. This was
easily the best billet of figured red gum eucalyptus I&#39;ve ever ran into, and the grafted walnut
billet was really nice too. I came up with a plan to make a very thin guitar using these woods.
The inside is hollow and the edges ended up very thin. Even with very heavy solid brass bridge,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenge, Walnut &amp; Cedar SF3 Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/wenge-walnut-cedar-sf3-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/wenge-walnut-cedar-sf3-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This was an instrument with a lot of experimental elements. One of the first polyester finishes, first time
mixing body wood, first time using magnets with the control cover, and first experience with the SD Invaders!
Many firsts, but few things I even returned to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swamp Ash SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/swamp-ash-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/swamp-ash-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This is a project that evolved a lot from start to finish, but one goal all along was to make a very light
guitar. This one-piece swamp ash body was light to start, but I had the face sliced off so we could
do some chambering and make it even lighter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gum Eucalyptus &amp; Walnut SF3 Singlecut Bass</title>
      <link>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass/</guid>
      <description>This bass was pretty important in the evolution of my designs as it was the first neck to utilize the
overlapping headcap with individual string guides. From here I moved onto a differnt design using solid
metal rivets instead of delrin rods, but this was still an important step. Some really nice local woods
again here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claro Walnut SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s an amazing thing when you get your first real customer. Working at the First Act Studio for Artists I had already worked on a good amount
of instruments for big names, and I was lucky enough to have some awesome musicians as friends that I had built for, but this was my first
real customer. We exchanged a few emails about the specs then one day a check showed up and I started building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beardburst Green SF0 Singlecut Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/beardburst-green-sf0-singlecut-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/beardburst-green-sf0-singlecut-guitar/</guid>
      <description>Spencer and I started talking about this guitar while I was still in Boston working at First Act.
We were hoping to get something going with their Studio for Artists program but it never panned out.
There&#39;s obviously a lot going on here... I think we hit some of the bullet points pretty well and others
lagged behind a bit. I know the stereo panning ability made it in to an album or two which is always</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gum Eucaluptus SF3 Singlecut Bass</title>
      <link>/instruments/red-gum-eucaluptus-sf3-singlecut-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/red-gum-eucaluptus-sf3-singlecut-bass/</guid>
      <description>This is the first instrument I built when I moved home to California. I setup most of my tools
while I was building this one so there are some rough edges, but it turned out pretty nice and
has been used plenty live and in the studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott&#39;s Old Guitars</title>
      <link>/instruments/scotts-old-guitars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/scotts-old-guitars/</guid>
      <description>Here are some guitars I made while attending The Roberto Venn School of Luthiery and my apprenticeship at the First Act Studio for Artists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
