<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sf3 on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/sf3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sf3 on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/sf3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Handmade Question</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/04/02/the-handmade-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/04/02/the-handmade-question/</guid>
      <description>The previous entry in this four part series found me reconnecting with the parts of lutherie that inspired me from the start and deciding to move forward with guitar building in ways I never considered. This entry is an extension of that reconsideration of all things held holy in guitar building. 
If you went back and looked at my first website from 2004, you&#39;d see I put a lot of emphasis on my instruments being handmade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SF3co Eco Guitar Prototype</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3co-eco-guitar-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3co-eco-guitar-prototype/</guid>
      <description>I started this prototype and the potential line of instruments it represented after taking a break from lutherie. It marked a shift in how I think about guitars and how I go about working on a project. Even though it was ultimately not a success, I did learn a lot about doing things I actually care about. The response to this instrument from potential customers was very strong and the fact that I didn&#39;t build a ton of them for excited customers really has more to do with my own personal situation starting a family and nothing to do with players&#39; appetite for &#39;alternative&#39; instruments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buckeye Burl SF3 Singlecut Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/buckeye-burl-sf3-singlecut-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/buckeye-burl-sf3-singlecut-guitar/</guid>
      <description>My friend Ian called one day and let me know our local Salvation Army had an absolute unit of a buckeye burl table come in that week.
I dropped everything to go look and it ended up being several burls combined into one table using about 40 pounds of epoxy and fiberglass.
We ruined a chainsaw blade and bandsaw blade just getting this one blank out of the table, but it was well worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Paisley SF3 Leo Fender Tribute Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/pink-paisley-sf3-leo-fender-tribute-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/pink-paisley-sf3-leo-fender-tribute-guitar/</guid>
      <description>I built this guitar as a tribute to Leo Fender. Like every gutiar builder ever I love his material choices, simple solutions,
and timeless designs. I didn&#39;t want to lean all the way into the vintage trap though so I included some crazy 18v active
pickups. If I built this one again I would do an oiled &amp;amp; waxed bolt-on neck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claro Walnut SF3 Singlecut Bass Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This was the rare instrument I actuatlly built on spec and the whole thing just went quick and easy.
I lucked into this beautiful and THICK Claro Walnut body blank that just perfectly fit with this 
singlecut SF3 bodystyle. I already had all the hardware and electronics around so this project came together
in a matter of days. It ended up going to local person with some interesting stories and a great instrument</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redwood &amp; Maple SF3 Bowable Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/redwood-maple-sf3-bowable-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/redwood-maple-sf3-bowable-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This SF3 came with a fairly straightforward goal: to be easy to play with a bow.
Narrowing the SF3 design and doing an exagerated top carve ended up being the easy part...
findings pickups and a bridge to accomodate that extreme radius was more challenging.
Nordstrand was able to supply some custom NDC humbuckers with super staggered magnets for the pickups.
For the bridge I used Graphtech saddles and built a very custom ebony bridge by hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myrtle Burl SF3 Chambered Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/myrtle-burl-sf3-chambered-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/myrtle-burl-sf3-chambered-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This is another fun SF3 with further refinements of the bodyshape. I found the one-piece top on a road trip in the Pacific Northwest. Lots of nice bloodwood details on this one that pair really well with the myrtle. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenge &amp; Mahogany SF3 Chambered Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/wenge-mahogany-sf3-chambered-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/wenge-mahogany-sf3-chambered-guitar/</guid>
      <description>There was a time when it was very hard to find to find wenge locally so I generally grabbed
it whenever it did show up. With that spirit one day I visited my most local, small town lumber
store and found some HUGE wenge slabs with plenty of space for multiple one-piece tops. I bought
all the clean boards and have been using them ever since. For me this guitar really was all</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Limba &amp; Rosewood SF3 Chambered Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/black-limba-rosewood-sf3-chambered-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/black-limba-rosewood-sf3-chambered-guitar/</guid>
      <description>I don&#39;t generally aim for using woods that compeltely steal the show, but even with subdued blanks I feel
like that&#39;s what ended up happening here. This black limba top and rosewood neck combo just really popped and
everything came together nicely. This is a great build to highlight how material selection and more importantly
a creative cut list can really impact the outcome. My memory is this was was originally a one-piece flat-sawn</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myrtle &amp; Redwood SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/myrtle-redwood-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/myrtle-redwood-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This SF3 represents a big transition with the design of the headstock and heel being refinfed
quite a bit. It was also a really light one thanks to the chambered redwood body and myrtle top. 
The redwood came from a thrift shop table and the myrtle from a Pacific Northwest road trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bolivian Rosewood &amp; Butternut SF3 Travel Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/rosewood-butternut-sf3-travel-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/rosewood-butternut-sf3-travel-guitar/</guid>
      <description>I don&#39;t have any stats to back this up, but I am fairly certain this was my most popular
guitar. I still get random emails from people looking to pick one up. I&#39;m really happy with
the design and how the guitar turned out, but the Steinberger tuners are a little wonky so I was 
always considering different options for future travel guitars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headless SF3 Singlecut Synth Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/headless-sf3-singlecut-synth-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/headless-sf3-singlecut-synth-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This was a fun project with a lot of elements I had never worked with before. The active pickups and Roland synth setup were interesting and the headless hardware worked out well. This did inspire me to want to work on a more elegant headless setup as the hardware was a bit industrial in design and feel. All the black parts and the heavy headless hardware definitely gave this one a unique feel within my body of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gum Eucalyptus SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This guitar came about when I lucked into two really nice pieces of local wood. This was
easily the best billet of figured red gum eucalyptus I&#39;ve ever ran into, and the grafted walnut
billet was really nice too. I came up with a plan to make a very thin guitar using these woods.
The inside is hollow and the edges ended up very thin. Even with very heavy solid brass bridge,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenge, Walnut &amp; Cedar SF3 Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/wenge-walnut-cedar-sf3-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/wenge-walnut-cedar-sf3-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This was an instrument with a lot of experimental elements. One of the first polyester finishes, first time
mixing body wood, first time using magnets with the control cover, and first experience with the SD Invaders!
Many firsts, but few things I even returned to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gum Eucalyptus &amp; Walnut SF3 Singlecut Bass</title>
      <link>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass/</guid>
      <description>This bass was pretty important in the evolution of my designs as it was the first neck to utilize the
overlapping headcap with individual string guides. From here I moved onto a differnt design using solid
metal rivets instead of delrin rods, but this was still an important step. Some really nice local woods
again here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claro Walnut SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s an amazing thing when you get your first real customer. Working at the First Act Studio for Artists I had already worked on a good amount
of instruments for big names, and I was lucky enough to have some awesome musicians as friends that I had built for, but this was my first
real customer. We exchanged a few emails about the specs then one day a check showed up and I started building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gum Eucaluptus SF3 Singlecut Bass</title>
      <link>/instruments/red-gum-eucaluptus-sf3-singlecut-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/red-gum-eucaluptus-sf3-singlecut-bass/</guid>
      <description>This is the first instrument I built when I moved home to California. I setup most of my tools
while I was building this one so there are some rough edges, but it turned out pretty nice and
has been used plenty live and in the studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott&#39;s Old Guitars</title>
      <link>/instruments/scotts-old-guitars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/scotts-old-guitars/</guid>
      <description>Here are some guitars I made while attending The Roberto Venn School of Luthiery and my apprenticeship at the First Act Studio for Artists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
