<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto of an Electric Guitar Builder</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/04/09/manifesto-of-an-electric-guitar-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/04/09/manifesto-of-an-electric-guitar-builder/</guid>
      <description>The previous entry in this four part series found me questioning some long held beliefs around the value of handmade instruments and making the decision to use all the modern tools available to me. This final entry outlines some of the other important choices that help shape my instruments. 
There&#39;s a famous document in the software world that was authored and co-signed by many of the most influential developers in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Handmade Question</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/04/02/the-handmade-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/04/02/the-handmade-question/</guid>
      <description>The previous entry in this four part series found me reconnecting with the parts of lutherie that inspired me from the start and deciding to move forward with guitar building in ways I never considered. This entry is an extension of that reconsideration of all things held holy in guitar building. 
If you went back and looked at my first website from 2004, you&#39;d see I put a lot of emphasis on my instruments being handmade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconnecting With Inspiration</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/03/26/reconnecting-with-inspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/03/26/reconnecting-with-inspiration/</guid>
      <description>The previous entry in this four part series found me questioning my place in the guitar world and eventually leaving to pursue other endeavors. We pick up almost ten years later when my therapist encouraged me to revisit lutherie looking for some long lost seeds of joy. 
I never really stopped thinking about guitars during the time I was away, but with work and family all I really had time for in the guitar world was thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Age Of Lutherie</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/03/19/the-golden-age-of-lutherie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/03/19/the-golden-age-of-lutherie/</guid>
      <description>We&#39;re living through what is often called The Golden Age of Lutherie. Whereas in the past luthiers and large companies tended to guard their secrets, we&#39;ve seen an explosion of communication and information sharing that raised the standard for modern instrument building. There are so many quality instruments being offered by so many great builders (both large and small) that the options are really overwhelming. Beyond all the familiar big names and the many popular smaller builders, the quality of instruments coming out of the East has been on the rise for the past 30 years as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
