<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chambered on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/chambered/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chambered on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/chambered/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chambered Claro Walnut SF3 Carve Top Guitar</title>
      <link>/in-progress/chambered-claro-walnut-sf3-carve-top-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/in-progress/chambered-claro-walnut-sf3-carve-top-guitar/</guid>
      <description>The first step toward a new generation of SF3 Guitars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redwood SF2 Chambered Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/redwood-sf2-chambered-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/redwood-sf2-chambered-guitar/</guid>
      <description>I could write a lot about this guitar, but ultimately I&#39;ll just say that trying to finish the burl redwood I used for the top
had me questioning my choice to ever get involved with guitar building. In the end, finish problems aside this guitar ended
up being pretty cool and sounding really good. The SF2 is a scaled down acoustic guitar design, but really it is too
traditional for me at this point and I doubt I will go any further down this path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buckeye Burl SF3 Singlecut Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/buckeye-burl-sf3-singlecut-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/buckeye-burl-sf3-singlecut-guitar/</guid>
      <description>My friend Ian called one day and let me know our local Salvation Army had an absolute unit of a buckeye burl table come in that week.
I dropped everything to go look and it ended up being several burls combined into one table using about 40 pounds of epoxy and fiberglass.
We ruined a chainsaw blade and bandsaw blade just getting this one blank out of the table, but it was well worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redwood &amp; Maple SF3 Bowable Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/redwood-maple-sf3-bowable-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/redwood-maple-sf3-bowable-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This SF3 came with a fairly straightforward goal: to be easy to play with a bow.
Narrowing the SF3 design and doing an exagerated top carve ended up being the easy part...
findings pickups and a bridge to accomodate that extreme radius was more challenging.
Nordstrand was able to supply some custom NDC humbuckers with super staggered magnets for the pickups.
For the bridge I used Graphtech saddles and built a very custom ebony bridge by hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myrtle Burl SF3 Chambered Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/myrtle-burl-sf3-chambered-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/myrtle-burl-sf3-chambered-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This is another fun SF3 with further refinements of the bodyshape. I found the one-piece top on a road trip in the Pacific Northwest. Lots of nice bloodwood details on this one that pair really well with the myrtle. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenge &amp; Mahogany SF3 Chambered Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/wenge-mahogany-sf3-chambered-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/wenge-mahogany-sf3-chambered-guitar/</guid>
      <description>There was a time when it was very hard to find to find wenge locally so I generally grabbed
it whenever it did show up. With that spirit one day I visited my most local, small town lumber
store and found some HUGE wenge slabs with plenty of space for multiple one-piece tops. I bought
all the clean boards and have been using them ever since. For me this guitar really was all</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Limba &amp; Rosewood SF3 Chambered Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/black-limba-rosewood-sf3-chambered-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/black-limba-rosewood-sf3-chambered-guitar/</guid>
      <description>I don&#39;t generally aim for using woods that compeltely steal the show, but even with subdued blanks I feel
like that&#39;s what ended up happening here. This black limba top and rosewood neck combo just really popped and
everything came together nicely. This is a great build to highlight how material selection and more importantly
a creative cut list can really impact the outcome. My memory is this was was originally a one-piece flat-sawn</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myrtle &amp; Redwood SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/myrtle-redwood-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/myrtle-redwood-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This SF3 represents a big transition with the design of the headstock and heel being refinfed
quite a bit. It was also a really light one thanks to the chambered redwood body and myrtle top. 
The redwood came from a thrift shop table and the myrtle from a Pacific Northwest road trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gum Eucalyptus SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This guitar came about when I lucked into two really nice pieces of local wood. This was
easily the best billet of figured red gum eucalyptus I&#39;ve ever ran into, and the grafted walnut
billet was really nice too. I came up with a plan to make a very thin guitar using these woods.
The inside is hollow and the edges ended up very thin. Even with very heavy solid brass bridge,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swamp Ash SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/swamp-ash-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/swamp-ash-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This is a project that evolved a lot from start to finish, but one goal all along was to make a very light
guitar. This one-piece swamp ash body was light to start, but I had the face sliced off so we could
do some chambering and make it even lighter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
