<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>solidbody on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/solidbody/</link>
    <description>Recent content in solidbody on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/solidbody/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SF3co Eco Guitar Prototype</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3co-eco-guitar-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3co-eco-guitar-prototype/</guid>
      <description>I started this prototype and the potential line of instruments it represented after taking a break from lutherie. It marked a shift in how I think about guitars and how I go about working on a project. Even though it was ultimately not a success, I did learn a lot about doing things I actually care about. The response to this instrument from potential customers was very strong and the fact that I didn&#39;t build a ton of them for excited customers really has more to do with my own personal situation starting a family and nothing to do with players&#39; appetite for &#39;alternative&#39; instruments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Paisley SF3 Leo Fender Tribute Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/pink-paisley-sf3-leo-fender-tribute-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/pink-paisley-sf3-leo-fender-tribute-guitar/</guid>
      <description>I built this guitar as a tribute to Leo Fender. Like every gutiar builder ever I love his material choices, simple solutions,
and timeless designs. I didn&#39;t want to lean all the way into the vintage trap though so I included some crazy 18v active
pickups. If I built this one again I would do an oiled &amp;amp; waxed bolt-on neck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claro Walnut SF3 Singlecut Bass Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This was the rare instrument I actuatlly built on spec and the whole thing just went quick and easy.
I lucked into this beautiful and THICK Claro Walnut body blank that just perfectly fit with this 
singlecut SF3 bodystyle. I already had all the hardware and electronics around so this project came together
in a matter of days. It ended up going to local person with some interesting stories and a great instrument</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bolivian Rosewood &amp; Butternut SF3 Travel Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/rosewood-butternut-sf3-travel-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/rosewood-butternut-sf3-travel-guitar/</guid>
      <description>I don&#39;t have any stats to back this up, but I am fairly certain this was my most popular
guitar. I still get random emails from people looking to pick one up. I&#39;m really happy with
the design and how the guitar turned out, but the Steinberger tuners are a little wonky so I was 
always considering different options for future travel guitars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headless SF3 Singlecut Synth Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/headless-sf3-singlecut-synth-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/headless-sf3-singlecut-synth-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This was a fun project with a lot of elements I had never worked with before. The active pickups and Roland synth setup were interesting and the headless hardware worked out well. This did inspire me to want to work on a more elegant headless setup as the hardware was a bit industrial in design and feel. All the black parts and the heavy headless hardware definitely gave this one a unique feel within my body of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenge, Walnut &amp; Cedar SF3 Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/wenge-walnut-cedar-sf3-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/wenge-walnut-cedar-sf3-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This was an instrument with a lot of experimental elements. One of the first polyester finishes, first time
mixing body wood, first time using magnets with the control cover, and first experience with the SD Invaders!
Many firsts, but few things I even returned to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gum Eucalyptus &amp; Walnut SF3 Singlecut Bass</title>
      <link>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass/</guid>
      <description>This bass was pretty important in the evolution of my designs as it was the first neck to utilize the
overlapping headcap with individual string guides. From here I moved onto a differnt design using solid
metal rivets instead of delrin rods, but this was still an important step. Some really nice local woods
again here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claro Walnut SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s an amazing thing when you get your first real customer. Working at the First Act Studio for Artists I had already worked on a good amount
of instruments for big names, and I was lucky enough to have some awesome musicians as friends that I had built for, but this was my first
real customer. We exchanged a few emails about the specs then one day a check showed up and I started building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beardburst Green SF0 Singlecut Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/beardburst-green-sf0-singlecut-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/beardburst-green-sf0-singlecut-guitar/</guid>
      <description>Spencer and I started talking about this guitar while I was still in Boston working at First Act.
We were hoping to get something going with their Studio for Artists program but it never panned out.
There&#39;s obviously a lot going on here... I think we hit some of the bullet points pretty well and others
lagged behind a bit. I know the stereo panning ability made it in to an album or two which is always</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott&#39;s Old Guitars</title>
      <link>/instruments/scotts-old-guitars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/scotts-old-guitars/</guid>
      <description>Here are some guitars I made while attending The Roberto Venn School of Luthiery and my apprenticeship at the First Act Studio for Artists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
