<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>imbuia on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/imbuia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in imbuia on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/imbuia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Imbuia &amp; Wicker Thiele Compact Ported Cab</title>
      <link>/journal/2021/01/04/mesa-boogie-thiele-imbuia-cabinet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2021/01/04/mesa-boogie-thiele-imbuia-cabinet/</guid>
      <description>This is the Holy Grail of Mesa cabs, a vintage hardwood &amp; wicker Thiele with Electro-Voice EVM-12L from 1987. When you consider this thing is over 30 years old it is in pretty nice shape. It was made using amazing 13&#34; wide imbuia boards. Condition is pretty nice overall. There are dents and dings throughout, but overall it presents pretty well. Weight is 48lbs. I&#39;ve purchased this cab twice and both times it was poorly packaged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1999 Taylor/Klein Imbuia AB-2 Acoustic Bass Guitar</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/09/22/1999-taylor-klein-ab-2-imbuia-acoustic-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/09/22/1999-taylor-klein-ab-2-imbuia-acoustic-bass/</guid>
      <description>I picked this up recently after about 20 years of wanting one. It&#39;s absolutely the nicest acoustic bass guitar I have played... but after owning it for a few weeks I think it is actually a little too nice for me. Oddly enough after so long waiting I lucked into a good deal on an another one of these (AB-1) that needs some work. I am going to let this one go and keep the one that needs some work as I am more of a tweaker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Thiele Ported Compact Cab in Imbuia Hardwood &amp; Wicker</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/01/09/mesa-boogie-thiele-cabinet-imbuia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/01/09/mesa-boogie-thiele-cabinet-imbuia/</guid>
      <description>This is the Holy Grail of Mesa cabs, a vintage hardwood &amp; wicker Thiele with EVM-12L from the Mark III era. When you consider this thing is around 30 years old it is in pretty nice shape. It was made using amazing 13&#34; wide imbuia boards. Condition is pretty nice overall. There are dents and dings throughout, and also some substantial scratches on top from amp feet. The speaker and it has a 1989 date code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1994 Mesa Boogie Imbuia &amp; Wicker Half-Back Speaker Cab</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/01/08/mesa-boogie-imbuia-half-back-cabinet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/01/08/mesa-boogie-imbuia-half-back-cabinet/</guid>
      <description>This is a beautiful hardwood &amp; wicker speaker cabinet from Mesa Engineering. It&#39;s a half-back with an EVM-12L from 1994. Between the year and the logo plate this looks like something that would have been bundled with a Mark IV. I can see from inside that at some point a speaker was rear mounted in this cab. Based on the foam left behind I would guess it was a C90. Around this time an EVM-12L would have the black sticker so this may be an older non-original speaker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Imbuia Hardwood &amp; Wicker Thiele Ported Compact Cab</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/11/25/mesa-boogie-imbuia-thiele-ported-cab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/11/25/mesa-boogie-imbuia-thiele-ported-cab/</guid>
      <description>This is the Holy Grail of Mesa cabs, a vintage hardwood &amp; wicker Thiele compact cab with the original EVM-12L. This one is in Imbuia and the figure is gorgeous. Judging from the logo plate and jack style I would guess this is from the mid to late eighties. The condition is solid, but a little rough around the edges. Someone definitely loved this cab and got a lot of use out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1993 Imbuia Hardwood &amp; Wicker Mesa Boogie Mark IV Compact Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2014/12/07/imbuia-mesa-boogie-mark-iv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2014/12/07/imbuia-mesa-boogie-mark-iv/</guid>
      <description>Here is a beautiful Mark IV from 1993. This is the &#34;A&#34; version which can be distinguished by the attached power cord and lack of foot switchable reverb.
The upside to the &#34;A&#34; version amps is the lead
channel voicing is closer to the original IIC+. This is a imbuia wood cabinet with wicker grill and it is the &#34;compact&#34;
cab size. The great looks and small size makes for a perfect living room combo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
