<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>claro on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/claro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in claro on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/claro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chambered Claro Walnut SF3 Carve Top Guitar</title>
      <link>/in-progress/chambered-claro-walnut-sf3-carve-top-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/in-progress/chambered-claro-walnut-sf3-carve-top-guitar/</guid>
      <description>The first step toward a new generation of SF3 Guitars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SF3co Eco Guitar Prototype</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3co-eco-guitar-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3co-eco-guitar-prototype/</guid>
      <description>I started this prototype and the potential line of instruments it represented after taking a break from lutherie. It marked a shift in how I think about guitars and how I go about working on a project. Even though it was ultimately not a success, I did learn a lot about doing things I actually care about. The response to this instrument from potential customers was very strong and the fact that I didn&#39;t build a ton of them for excited customers really has more to do with my own personal situation starting a family and nothing to do with players&#39; appetite for &#39;alternative&#39; instruments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SF3co: Eco Friendly Guitar</title>
      <link>/journal/2010/11/07/sf3co-eco-friendly-electric-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2010/11/07/sf3co-eco-friendly-electric-guitar/</guid>
      <description>The most important thing to do in your life is to not interfere with somebody else&#39;s life.
 Frank Zappa   I doubt Zappa had any kind of ecological issues in mind when he said this but I&#39;ll happily quote one of my heroes when his words sum up my feelings so perfectly. Background: The Problem When I first became interested in guitars and music I had no idea where the materials for new instruments came from or who made them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claro Walnut SF3 Singlecut Bass Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This was the rare instrument I actuatlly built on spec and the whole thing just went quick and easy.
I lucked into this beautiful and THICK Claro Walnut body blank that just perfectly fit with this 
singlecut SF3 bodystyle. I already had all the hardware and electronics around so this project came together
in a matter of days. It ended up going to local person with some interesting stories and a great instrument</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gum Eucalyptus SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This guitar came about when I lucked into two really nice pieces of local wood. This was
easily the best billet of figured red gum eucalyptus I&#39;ve ever ran into, and the grafted walnut
billet was really nice too. I came up with a plan to make a very thin guitar using these woods.
The inside is hollow and the edges ended up very thin. Even with very heavy solid brass bridge,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gum Eucalyptus &amp; Walnut SF3 Singlecut Bass</title>
      <link>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-walnut-sf3-singlecut-bass/</guid>
      <description>This bass was pretty important in the evolution of my designs as it was the first neck to utilize the
overlapping headcap with individual string guides. From here I moved onto a differnt design using solid
metal rivets instead of delrin rods, but this was still an important step. Some really nice local woods
again here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claro Walnut SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s an amazing thing when you get your first real customer. Working at the First Act Studio for Artists I had already worked on a good amount
of instruments for big names, and I was lucky enough to have some awesome musicians as friends that I had built for, but this was my first
real customer. We exchanged a few emails about the specs then one day a check showed up and I started building.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
