<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lapin-d&#39;eau on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/lapin-deau/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lapin-d&#39;eau on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/lapin-deau/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>February 2023 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2023/02/28/february-2023-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2023/02/28/february-2023-update/</guid>
      <description>February started with a bang and ended with a whimper. All of January&#39;s forward progress carried over to the new month with several objects being modelled and machined. I refined the pickup cover design a bit and also moved into the recessed pickup rings. From there I made some good progress on a two-piece knob design. Here&#39;s a short video showing how quick you&#39;re able to take an idea from paper to a physical object with all these awesome modern tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 2023 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2023/01/31/january-2023-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2023/01/31/january-2023-update/</guid>
      <description>January was a great month full of learning, and as a result some new progress was made on the next SF3! I&#39;ve wanted to learn 3D CAD/CAM for many years but have always been intimidated by the complexity. It was a great moment when I found out that I could do simple 2.5D CAD/CAM using Illustrator SVGs when I first got the CNC. Being able to work with software and concepts that I was already familiar with was great because it allowed me focused on the initial challenge of learning how to run a CNC and use basic CAD/CAM software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/11/21/november-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/11/21/november-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>Fall is upon us and another busy time of year has come again. I missed the October website update and November is almost over! In October my family got a new Great Dane puppy named Juno. For now she&#39;s a lot of work (and puppies can be quite annoying), but we&#39;re looking forward to her being a great companion to our older Dane, Freya. Lots of family joy celebrating the new crew member and learning how to best take care of her together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/09/22/september-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/09/22/september-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick update for September. I&#39;ve added a few new backlogged journal updates with more old Boogie photos as well as a very strange Atlansia instrument. Check those out here: 1994 Atlansia Solitaire Single String Bass
Mesa Boogie Dual Rectifier Trem-o-verb Hardwood Combo
Mesa Boogie Collection Odds and Ends On the topic of the new SF3, it is moving along slowly but steadily. The plans are nearly done and I have made some solid progress in getting the new pickups all sorted and ready to start building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/08/31/august-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/08/31/august-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>All things considered August was a good month on the guitar front. I started the month working on my first ever pedalboard. I have been collecting parts and planning for years but it&#39;s finally time to put it all together. Almost immediately I ran into shipping delays on some essential parts so the project is currently on hold, but I hope to finish the first version in September if there are no more delays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chambered Claro Walnut SF3 Carve Top Guitar</title>
      <link>/in-progress/chambered-claro-walnut-sf3-carve-top-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/in-progress/chambered-claro-walnut-sf3-carve-top-guitar/</guid>
      <description>The first step toward a new generation of SF3 Guitars.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
