<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>may-2022-update on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/may-2022-update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in may-2022-update on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/may-2022-update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>May 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/05/28/may-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/05/28/may-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>Before I launched this new site in April my hope was I would be able to to make a new journal entry each week, but during the process of getting the site finished and released I realized once per month was much more likely. April was a busy month with my wife Brianna away most of the time working a new mural. May turned out to be just as busy with several small building projects, an overnight class field trip, and lots of other family, work, and house projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Pickup for Christian Allen Luthiery</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/05/24/custom-pickup-christian-allen-luthiery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/05/24/custom-pickup-christian-allen-luthiery/</guid>
      <description>Christian is a great local luthier and fellow Roberto-Venn graduate. He&#39;s been building some really interesting instruments recently and this is the third custom pickup I&#39;ve made for him. For this project he needed a magnetic humbucking pickup to cover only three closely spaced strings. This post gives you an idea of how these projects can go. I recieve some basic dimensions from Christian, then digitize those in Adobe Illustrator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milkman 5W Half Pint Head with Mather Cab in Walnut </title>
      <link>/journal/2022/02/07/milkman-half-pint-walnut-head-mather-cab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/02/07/milkman-half-pint-walnut-head-mather-cab/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;ve dug through the archived journal entries here or seen my Instagram feed you know that I&#39;ve owned a lot of Mesa Boogie amps and cabs. I love the way they sound and love that they are made in California, but I always ran into two problems. One, they are universally very heavy amps. That&#39;s not a terrible thing if you want something really well made and road worthy, but my gear doesn&#39;t move around too much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1994 Mesa Boogie Imbuia &amp; Wicker Half-Back Speaker Cab</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/01/08/mesa-boogie-imbuia-half-back-cabinet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/01/08/mesa-boogie-imbuia-half-back-cabinet/</guid>
      <description>This is a beautiful hardwood &amp; wicker speaker cabinet from Mesa Engineering. It&#39;s a half-back with an EVM-12L from 1994. Between the year and the logo plate this looks like something that would have been bundled with a Mark IV. I can see from inside that at some point a speaker was rear mounted in this cab. Based on the foam left behind I would guess it was a C90. Around this time an EVM-12L would have the black sticker so this may be an older non-original speaker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coilton the Accuwinder CW-11B Coil Winding Machine</title>
      <link>/journal/2018/11/18/accuwinder-pickup-winder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2018/11/18/accuwinder-pickup-winder/</guid>
      <description>This was a serendipitous find. Years ago my therapist suggested I spend more idle time in the evening without a digital device in front of me. It took a while before I gave it a fair shot, but upon trying it out my mind started filling up with new ideas almost immediately. Very quickly it became obvious I needed a pickup winder to start working through some of these ideas. I had looked at buying winders before but they always felt fairly expensive for the limited functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Imbuia Hardwood &amp; Wicker Thiele Ported Compact Cab</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/11/25/mesa-boogie-imbuia-thiele-ported-cab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/11/25/mesa-boogie-imbuia-thiele-ported-cab/</guid>
      <description>This is the Holy Grail of Mesa cabs, a vintage hardwood &amp; wicker Thiele compact cab with the original EVM-12L. This one is in Imbuia and the figure is gorgeous. Judging from the logo plate and jack style I would guess this is from the mid to late eighties. The condition is solid, but a little rough around the edges. Someone definitely loved this cab and got a lot of use out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark IIC&#43; Simul-Class, GEQ, Hardwood Medium Head</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/09/06/mesa-boogie-mark-iic-plus-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/09/06/mesa-boogie-mark-iic-plus-head/</guid>
      <description>This is a holy grail kind of amp on multiple fronts. IIC+/Simul-Class/GEQ is the most desired vintage Boogie by far, and for the hardwood fans these medium head shells in hardwood/wicker are almost never to be found, and the 415/416 power tube combo is the best for vintage Simul-Class Boogies. STR-415s are not common, but STR-416s have become VERY rare. On top of that, we have all the original paperwork. The tubes are tested and matching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Lone Star Special Tasmanian Blackwood Hardwood Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/09/04/tasmanian-blackwood-mesa-boogie-lone-star-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/09/04/tasmanian-blackwood-mesa-boogie-lone-star-special/</guid>
      <description>This Mesa Boogie Lone Star Special features a fairly uncommon Tasmanian Blackwood hardwood combo cabinet.
Lots of tonal options and the great MC-90 speaker. Another one that got away but you can&#39;t keep them all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
