<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>babygrand on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/babygrand/</link>
    <description>Recent content in babygrand on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/babygrand/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SF3co Eco Guitar Prototype</title>
      <link>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3co-eco-guitar-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/claro-walnut-sf3co-eco-guitar-prototype/</guid>
      <description>I started this prototype and the potential line of instruments it represented after taking a break from lutherie. It marked a shift in how I think about guitars and how I go about working on a project. Even though it was ultimately not a success, I did learn a lot about doing things I actually care about. The response to this instrument from potential customers was very strong and the fact that I didn&#39;t build a ton of them for excited customers really has more to do with my own personal situation starting a family and nothing to do with players&#39; appetite for &#39;alternative&#39; instruments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myrtle Burl SF3 Chambered Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/myrtle-burl-sf3-chambered-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/myrtle-burl-sf3-chambered-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This is another fun SF3 with further refinements of the bodyshape. I found the one-piece top on a road trip in the Pacific Northwest. Lots of nice bloodwood details on this one that pair really well with the myrtle. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenge &amp; Mahogany SF3 Chambered Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/wenge-mahogany-sf3-chambered-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/wenge-mahogany-sf3-chambered-guitar/</guid>
      <description>There was a time when it was very hard to find to find wenge locally so I generally grabbed
it whenever it did show up. With that spirit one day I visited my most local, small town lumber
store and found some HUGE wenge slabs with plenty of space for multiple one-piece tops. I bought
all the clean boards and have been using them ever since. For me this guitar really was all</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Limba &amp; Rosewood SF3 Chambered Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/black-limba-rosewood-sf3-chambered-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/black-limba-rosewood-sf3-chambered-guitar/</guid>
      <description>I don&#39;t generally aim for using woods that compeltely steal the show, but even with subdued blanks I feel
like that&#39;s what ended up happening here. This black limba top and rosewood neck combo just really popped and
everything came together nicely. This is a great build to highlight how material selection and more importantly
a creative cut list can really impact the outcome. My memory is this was was originally a one-piece flat-sawn</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myrtle &amp; Redwood SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/myrtle-redwood-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/myrtle-redwood-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This SF3 represents a big transition with the design of the headstock and heel being refinfed
quite a bit. It was also a really light one thanks to the chambered redwood body and myrtle top. 
The redwood came from a thrift shop table and the myrtle from a Pacific Northwest road trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gum Eucalyptus SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/red-gum-eucalyptus-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This guitar came about when I lucked into two really nice pieces of local wood. This was
easily the best billet of figured red gum eucalyptus I&#39;ve ever ran into, and the grafted walnut
billet was really nice too. I came up with a plan to make a very thin guitar using these woods.
The inside is hollow and the edges ended up very thin. Even with very heavy solid brass bridge,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenge, Walnut &amp; Cedar SF3 Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/wenge-walnut-cedar-sf3-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/wenge-walnut-cedar-sf3-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This was an instrument with a lot of experimental elements. One of the first polyester finishes, first time
mixing body wood, first time using magnets with the control cover, and first experience with the SD Invaders!
Many firsts, but few things I even returned to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swamp Ash SF3 Lightweight Guitar</title>
      <link>/instruments/swamp-ash-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/swamp-ash-sf3-lightweight-guitar/</guid>
      <description>This is a project that evolved a lot from start to finish, but one goal all along was to make a very light
guitar. This one-piece swamp ash body was light to start, but I had the face sliced off so we could
do some chambering and make it even lighter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
