<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>boire on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/boire/</link>
    <description>Recent content in boire on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/boire/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>March and April 2023 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2023/04/17/march-april-2023-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2023/04/17/march-april-2023-update/</guid>
      <description>March started slow with sickness and bad weather, then ended with even more snow. Throughout the month I continued making progress on digitizing the SF3 design into 3D for future CAD/CAM options. For now I will be doing a lot of the work on this next SF3 by hand because I don&#39;t want to waste any of this good weather on the computer. Speaking of the new SF3, there is some new progress here and at the project page below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1990 Boire Warwick Dolphin Pro I Bass</title>
      <link>/journal/2018/05/09/boire-warwick-dolphin-pro-1-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2018/05/09/boire-warwick-dolphin-pro-1-bass/</guid>
      <description>This is a no-compromise early Warwick Dolphin Pro I with all the best features. Being a 1990 it&#39;s still in the Warwick &#34;handmade&#34; era. It has the coveted Boire Rosewood body instead of the later Ovangkol. Bartolini J+MM Pickups and 2-Band Pre-amp instead of later MEC. Satin Chrome (also called titanium or platinum) hardware including Schaller strap locks. 7-piece Wenge/Zebrano neck WITHOUT the volute like the later Dolphins. No modifications, missing pieces, or weird custom features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott&#39;s Old Guitars</title>
      <link>/instruments/scotts-old-guitars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instruments/scotts-old-guitars/</guid>
      <description>Here are some guitars I made while attending The Roberto Venn School of Luthiery and my apprenticeship at the First Act Studio for Artists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
