<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>november-2022-update on Scott French</title>
    <link>/tags/november-2022-update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in november-2022-update on Scott French</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/november-2022-update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>November 2022 Update</title>
      <link>/journal/2022/11/21/november-2022-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2022/11/21/november-2022-update/</guid>
      <description>Fall is upon us and another busy time of year has come again. I missed the October website update and November is almost over! In October my family got a new Great Dane puppy named Juno. For now she&#39;s a lot of work (and puppies can be quite annoying), but we&#39;re looking forward to her being a great companion to our older Dane, Freya. Lots of family joy celebrating the new crew member and learning how to best take care of her together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark III / IIIC&#43; with 105PT &amp; STR-415/416 Imbuia</title>
      <link>/journal/2019/03/29/mesa-boogie-mark-iiic-plus-drg-imbuia-combo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2019/03/29/mesa-boogie-mark-iiic-plus-drg-imbuia-combo/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;re looking for the best possible Mark III then you can stop here, you&#39;ve found it. This is a 1985 Mesa Boogie Mark III. It&#39;s an early no-stripe version released just after the Mark IIC+, and being a transition model they share a few common elements. The 105 power transformer and heavier faceplate are carried over from the IIC+. This is a DRG, meaning Simul-class, Reverb, and Graphic EQ options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark III Black Stripe DRG Imbuia Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/09/03/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-black-stripe-drg-imbuia-combo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/09/03/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-black-stripe-drg-imbuia-combo/</guid>
      <description>This is a 1985 MESA/Boogie Mark III Combo. It is a DRG model, which means Simul-Class power section, Reverb, and Graphic EQ. This is a black/no-stripe revision which is the first of the Mark IIIs. Some early black/no-stripe examples share several features with the Mark IIC+. First, this amp has the early-style etched face plate where all the lines and text are metal instead of white paint. These hold up a lot better than the painted face plates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark III Blue Stripe DRG Imbuia Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2017/03/14/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-blue-stripe-drg-imbuia-combo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2017/03/14/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-blue-stripe-drg-imbuia-combo/</guid>
      <description>You&#39;re looking at a 1988 Mesa Boogie Mark III Blue Stripe Combo. It is a DRG, meaning Simul-class power, Reverb, and Graphic EQ. It also has an Electro-Voice EVM-12L 12&#34; speaker. The cabinet is unmarked, but it looks like other cabinets I&#39;ve had that were marked Imbuia. This is basically a fully loaded Mark III with all the preferred features. On top of all that, it already has the factory R2 volume mod and reverb fix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesa Boogie Mark III Purple Stripe DRG Imbuia Combo</title>
      <link>/journal/2016/10/20/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-purple-stripe-drg-imbuia-combo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/2016/10/20/mesa-boogie-mark-iii-purple-stripe-drg-imbuia-combo/</guid>
      <description>This is a 1986 Mesa Boogie Mark III Purple Stripe Combo in Imbuya and Wicker. As far as I know this amp is 100% original. Features include Graphic EQ, Reverb, and Simul-Class which would make this a DRG. Also includes the iconic Electro Voice EVM-12L speaker. Chassis mount is SUS-4. Original vinyl cover is quite worn out. Does the job but doesn&#39;t look very good. You can judge the condition for yourself based on the photos.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
